Guide to the McGraw-Hill Marketing Information Center Vertical File, 1948-1991
The John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising & Marketing History David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library Duke University Durham, N.C., USA
- Marketing Series (MKT), 20 Boxes
  - MKT 0. MARKETING: ROLE AND GENERAL THEORY OF MARKETING
    See also: MKT 5, MARKETING CONCEPTS, miscellaneous subsections; IOP 10, INTERNATIONAL MARKETING, miscellaneous subsections for comparative marketing concepts and systems
    - MKT 0:1 Marketing Issues (historical and contemporary), Practices and Theories, in combination or N.E.C.
    - MKT 0:1 Marketing Issues (historical and contemporary), Practices and Theories, in combination or N.E.C. (Box 55)
    - MKT 0:2 Marketing: Science or Process?
    - MKT 0:3 Industrial vs. Consumer: Marketing Differences (includes information on industrial goods marketing)
      See also MKT 50:2-4, Market Analysis and Sales Forecasting, all subsections
      - 0:3-1 Industrial vs. Consumer Markets: Size Estimates (includes Beckman and other similar studies)
    - MKT 0:4 Metamarketing: The Furthering (marketing) of Organizations, Persons, Places, Causes, Services (includes information on such things as the advertising of fees and services by professionals)
      See also MKT 5:2-10, Social/Ethical Responsibility Concept
    - MKT 0:5 Retailing/Wholesaling/Merchandising
      See also: ADV 50:6, Merchandising, selected subsections
      - 0:5-1 Cents-Off Couponing
    - MKT 0:6 Terms and Definitions
      See also: MKT 50:1-2, Marketing Research, Definitions and Terms; ADM 0:2-4.5.1, Dictionaries of Economic Terms; ADV 35:6, Media/Advertising Terms and Definitions
  - MKT 5. MARKETING CONCEPTS
    - MKT 5:1 Marketing Concepts, N.E.C. (theory and role of the original post-World War II concept; i.e., making the customer the focal point towards which all business activity is directed; includes commentary on issues, applications and proposed deepening, broadening, and furthering of the basic concept)
    - MKT 5:2 Marketing Concept Variations (Box 56)
      - 5:2-1 Barter Trading Concept (reciprocal dealing)
      - 5:2-2 Brand and Product Line Concept
        See also: MKT 40:1-3, Brand/Product/Project, etc., Management, and all subsections
      - 5:2-3 Customer Service Concept
      - 5:2-4 Demarketing Concept
        See also: MKT 45, MARKETING IN AN ABNORMAL ECONOMY
      - 5:2-5 Generic Concept
      - 5:2-6 Marketcentering Concept
      - 5:2-7 Marketing Mix Concept (includes information on the overall topic marketing communications)
        See also: MKT 5:2-11, Systems Concept and subsections
      - [Metamarketing Concept--see: MKT 0:4, Metamarketing]
      - 5:2-8 Pooled Marketing Concept
      - 5:2-9 Positioning Concept (includes information on repositioning old products)
        See also: ADV 50:4-3.8, Copy: Comparative/Comparison
      - 5:2-10 Social/Ethical Responsibility Concept
        See also: ADM 0:2-10.32, Social and Ethical Responsibilty, Corporate; ADV 25, DECEPTION, ETHICS, TRUTH AND TASTE IN ADVERTISING, miscellaneous subsections; MKT 35:3, Consumerism; MKT 50:6, Ethics in Marketing Research
      - 5:2-11 Systems Concept
        - 5:2-11.1 Systems-Selling Sub Concept
      - 5:2-12 Vertical Integration/Scrambled-Marketing/Dual Distribution Concept
        See also: MKT 20:2, Channel Analysis Management and Theory
  - MKT 10. COSTS: MARKETING AND DISTRIBUTION
    See also: MKT 50:1-1, Marketing Research Costs; MKT 55, PRICING; SAL 20, SALES COSTS, all subsections
    - MKT 10:1 Cost Analysis and Determination (financial dimension of marketing), N.E.C.
      - 10:1-1 Marketing Audits
    - MKT 10:2 Cost Reduction
    - MKT 10:3 Marketing Costs/Sales Ratios
    - MKT 10:4 Small Orders: Problems and Solutions
  - MKT 15. METRICATION IN MARKETING
    - MKT 15:1 Current Status and General Impact of Conversion
      - 15:1-1 By-Industry Conversion Status and Impact
    - MKT 15:2 Sources of Instructional Materials (Box 57)
  - MKT 20. DISTRIBUTION
    - MKT 20:1 Distribution Concepts and Methods, N.E.C.
      See also: MKT 5, MARKETING CONCEPTS, miscellaneous subsections
    - MKT 20:2 Channel Analysis Management and Theory
      See also: MKT 5:2-12, Vertical Integration/Scrambled-Marketing/Dual Distribution Concept
    - MKT 20:3 Education in and for Distribution
      See also: ADM 0:2-8.21, Training and Development, miscellaneous subsections; MKT 40:3, Marketing/Communications, Careers, Education, Recruitment, Training and Development, miscellaneous subsections
    - MKT 20:4 Franchised Distribution (Franchising) (includes licensing)
    - MKT 20:5 Inventory Management
    - MKT 20:6 Percent of Sales by Channel of Distribution
    - MKT 20:7 Physical Distribution (marketing logistics; includes information on physical distribution management)
    - MKT 20:8 Traffic, Transportation and Distribution: Departments and Management, N.E.C.
      See also: MKT 20:7, Physical Distribution
    - MKT 20:9 Distributors
      - 20:9-1 Distributors: Their Place in Industry (includes distribution compensation data)
      - 20:9-2 Organizing and Building a Distributor System
        - 20:9-2.1 Selecting and Evaluating Distributors
      - 20:9-3 Lines Handled by Distributors
      - 20:9-4 Operations Surveys
      - 20:9-5 Dealer Margins/Commissions/Motivation
        See also: MKT 20:10-5, Manufacturers' Agents and Representatives, Commission Rates; SAL 20:2, 20:3, and 20:3-1, Sales Compensation; SAL 15:5, Motivating the (Sales) Staff, all subsections
      - 20:9-6 Distributor Promotion
        See also: ADV 50:4-3.11, Copy Approaches and Themes, Distributor; ADV 50:6-2, Merchandising to Distributors
      - 20:9-7 Manufacturer/Distributor Relations, N.E.C.
        - 20:9-7.1 Distributor Training
          See also: SAL 35, SALES TRAINING AND DEVELOPMENT, and references contained there
      - 20:9-8 Distributor/Customer Relations
      - 20:9-9 Distributors' and Manufacturers' Agents' Salespeople
        See also SAL, Sales, all headings
    - MKT 20:10 Manufacturers' Agents and Representatives
      See also: MKT 20:9-9, Distributors' and Manufacturers' Agents' Salespeople; SAL, Sales, all headings
      - 20:10-1 Role and Operation, N.E.C. (Box 58)
        See also: MKT 20:9-9, Distributors' and Manufacturers' Agents' Salespeople
      - 20:10-2 Finding, Selecting, Hiring Manufacturers' Agents
        - 20:10-2.1 Manufacturer-Agent/Representative Agreements
      - 20:10-3 Agents/Representatives vs. Company Sales Force
      - 20:10-4 Manufacturer-Agent/Representative Relations
      - 20:10-5 Commission Rates
        See also: MKT 20:9-5, Dealer Margins/Commissions/Motivation; SAL 20:2, 20:3, 20:3-1, Sales Compensation
  - MKT 25. EXHIBITS AND SHOWS
    - MKT 25:1 Exhibits and Shows as a Marketing Medium
      See also: IOP 10:2-11, Exhibiting Overseas, N.E.C., and selected subsections
    - MKT 25:2 Show Selection and Participation Procedures
    - MKT 25:3 Trade Show Trends: Annual Audience Statistics, Quality and Activity Indicators
    - MKT 25:4 Exhibit Planning, Management and Operation
      - 25:4-1 Exhibit Planning, Management and Operation, N.E.C.
      - 25:4-2 Auditing Procedures: Audience Measurement, Exhibit Effectiveness/Evaluation Yardsticks
      - 25:4-3 Budgeting and Cost Control
      - 25:4-4 Hospitality Suites
        See also: ADM 0:2-7.2.5, Conferences, Conventions, Seminars and Meetings, all subsections
      - 25:4-5 Security
    - MKT 25:5 Mobile Exhibits and Shows
    - [Overseas Exhibiting--see: IOP 10:2-11]
  - MKT 30. PRODUCTIVITY IN MARKETING
    See also: ADM 0:2-4.12, Productivity, and subsections
  - MKT 35. LEGAL ASPECTS OF MARKETING
    See also: ADM 0:2-10.32, Social and Ethical Responsibilities, Corporate; ADV 25, DECEPTION, ETHICS, TRUTH AND TASTE IN ADVERTISING, miscellaneous subsections; ADV 30, LEGAL ASPECTS OF ADVERTISING; IOP 10:2-3, Global Challenges to Advertising; MKT 5:2-10, Social Responsibility Concept
    - MKT 35:1 Legal Aspects and Restrictive Regulations, N.E.C. (includes general information on government and marketing)
    - MKT 35:2 Fair Trade
    - MKT 35:3 Consumerism
      See also: specific topics listed under main heading and IOP 10:2-3, Global Challenges to Advertising; ADM 0:2-10.8, Consumer Affairs Departments; MKT 5:2-3, Customer Service Concept
    - MKT 35:4 Licensing Practices
      See also: IOP 5:5-3, Overseas Licensing/International Sales, Marketing Agreements
    - MKT 35:5 Product Liability/Safety/Testing/Warranties/Quality Control
      See also: ADM 0:2-4.12, Productivity, N.E.C.
    - MKT 35:6 Product Recalls (Box 59)
    - MKT 35:7 Value Added Taxation (VAT)
  - MKT 40. MARKETING/COMMUNICATIONS ADMINISTRATION
    See also: ADM, ADMINISTRATION, all subsections for general administrative techniques which may be used in a marketing environment; this classification deals solely with specific management activities in the marketing area. See also: ADM 0:2-10, Public Affairs/Relations, miscellaneous subsections; SAL, SALES all subsections, particularly those dealing with Sales Management, and especially SAL 30, SALES PROMOTION, all subsections
    - MKT 40:1 Marketing Functions
      - 40:1-1 Top Management's Role in Marketing
        See also: ADM 0:2-2, Presidents and CEOs
        - 40:1-1.1 The Chief Marketing Executive
      - 40:1-2 Marketing/Communications Management, N.E.C. (Box 60)
        - 40:1-2.1 Advertising Management
          See also: MKT 40:2, Marketing Department Organization, miscellaneous subsections
          - 40:1-2.1.1 Duties, Functions, Skills
          - 40:1-2.1.2 Home Life/Health/Personal Data
            See also: ADM 0:2-8.7, Health; MKT 40:3, Marketing/Communications, Careers, Education, Recruitment, Training and Development, miscellaneous subsections
          - 40:1-2.1.3 Statistical Profiles
            See also: MKT 40:1-8, Marketing Communications Functions Compensation
          - 40:1-2.1.4 Attitudes Towards Businesspapers
            See also: ADV 25, DECEPTION, ETHICS, TRUTH AND TASTE IN ADVERTISING, all subsections; ADV 15, ATTITUDES TOWARDS ADVERTISING, all subsections; IOP 10:2-3, Global Challenges to Advertising; MKT 35:3, Consumerism
          - 40:1-2.1.5 Corporate Media Directors
            See also: ADV 5:4-2, House Agencies; ADV 5:10-6, Media Staff: Buyers, Directors, Planners; ADV 5:12-3, Media Departments
      - 40:1-3 Brand/Product/Project, etc., Management
        - 40:1-3.1 Brand/Product Management
          - 40:1-3.1.1 Branding
            Branding is a subject which has its roots in many areas of marketing; for example, it has its place in trade names/trademarks, the generic concept part of the marketing concept, consumer purchasing motivation and decisions, and the determination of marketing strategies. It is, therefore, difficult to catalog material on the topic. In this file, documentation - mainly in the form of photocopies of material cataloged elsewhere - touching on branding in one way or another is brought together for easy reference. This section also features original documentation on branding when the text is too broad for finer classification. See also: ADM 0:2-10.22.1, Brandstanding.
        - 40:1-3.2 Materials Management
        - 40:1-3.3 Production/Project Management
      - 40:1-4 Financial/Credit Management
      - 40:1-5 Market Research Management
        See also: MKT 50, MARKETING RESEARCH, all subsections; MKT 40:3, Marketing/Communications Careers, Education, Recruitment, Training and Development, miscellaneous subsections; MKT 40:2, Marketing Department Organization, miscellaneous subsections
        - 40:1-5.1 Market Research Staff
          See also: MKT 40:3, Marketing/Communications Careers, Education, Recruitment, Training and Development, miscellaneous subsections
      - 40:1-6 Marketing Consultants
      - 40:1-7 Sales Promotion Management
        See also: SAL 30, SALES PROMOTION, all subsections; MKT 40:2, Marketing Department Organization, miscellaneous subsections
      - 40:1-8 Marketing Communications Functions Compensation (for key jobs in marketing, advertising, media, public relations)
        See also: ADM 0:2-8.4, Compensation: Executive/Management, all subsections; ADV 5:10-9, Advertising Agency Salaries; SAL 20:2, 20:3, 20:3-1, Sales Compensation
    - MKT 40:2 Marketing Department Organization (for sales departments, see: SAL 10:4, Sales Departments, all subsections)
      - 40:2-1 Marketing/Communications Departments, in combination or N.E.C. (Box 61)
        See also: ADM 0:2-10, Public Affairs/Relations, miscellaneous subsections
      - 40:2-2 Advertising Departments
        See also: MKT 40:1-2, Marketing/Communications Management, N.E.C. and subsections, particularly MKT 40:1-2.1, Advertising Management, and subsections
      - 40:2-3 Market Research Departments
        See also: MKT 40:1-2, Marketing/Communications Management, N.E.C., and subsections, particularly MKT 40:1-5, Market Research Management and MKT 40:1-7, Sales Promotion Management; SAL 30, SALES PROMOTION, all subsections
    - MKT 40:3 Marketing/Communications Careers, Education, Recruitment, Training and Development
      See also: ADM 0:2-8.21, Training and Development, miscellaneous subsections; ADV 5:10, Advertising Agencies, Personnel, miscellaneous subsections; MKT 20:3, Education in and for Distribution; SAL 5, THE SALES PROFESSION, all subsections
      - 40:3-1 Careers in Marketing, N.E.C.
        - 40:3-1.1 Ethnics/Minorities in Marketing
          See also: ADM 0:2-7.8, Ethnics/Minorities in Management; SAL 5:3, Ethnics/Minorities in Selling
        - 40:3-1.2 Women in Marketing
          See also: ADM 0:2-7.28, Women in Management; SAL 5:4, Women in Selling
      - 40:3-2 Careers in Communications, N.E.C.
        See also: preceding cross-references
        - 40:3-2.1 Ethnics/Minorities in Communications
        - 40:3-2.2 Women in Communications
        - 40:3-2.3 Communications Industry Actuarial Tables
      - 40:3-3 Education for Marketing, N.E.C.
        See also: ADM 0:2-8.21.5, Business Education, and subsection; SAL 5, THE SALES PROFESSION, for information on education for selling
        - 40:3-3.1 Education for Communications
      - 40:3-4 Recruitment, Training and Development for Marketing Communications, N.E.C.
        See also: ADM 0:2-8.16, Recruitment; ADM 0:2-8.21, Training and Development, all subsections; SAL 35, SALES RECRUITING, SELECTION AND TRAINING
    - MKT 40:4 Decision-Making in Marketing
      See also: ADM 0:2-7.6, Decision-Making; MKT 50:2, Techniques of Marketing Research, miscellaneous subsections
      - 40:4-1 Marketing Decision-Making, N.E.C. (includes information on cognitive dissonance in marketing)
        See also: ADM 0:2-7.6 for further information on cognitive dissonance
      - 40:4-2 Advertising Decision-Making
      - 40:4-3 Make or Buy Decisions
      - 40:4-4 Computers in Marketing (Box 62)
        See also: ADM 0:2-7.2.4, Computer Literacy
      - 40:4-5 Gaming and Modeling in Marketing: Theory and Commentary, N.E.C.
        - 40:4-5.1 Modeling and Gaming Techniques Designed for Specific Marketing Application Decisions (this classification should always be used in conjunction with other marketing subject areas: for example, researchers seeking information on marketing channel analysis should first consult MKT 20:2, Channel Analysis Management and Theory, then they would refer to this classification section for information on models developed for channel analysis)
    - MKT 40:5 Marketing Intelligence and Information Systems
      See also: ADM 0:2-7.2.6, Information Systems and Retrieval; ADM 0:2-10.32, Social and Ethical Responsibilities, Corporate; MKT 5:2-10, Social/Ethical Responsibility Concept; MKT 35:3, Consumerism; MKT 50:6, Ethics in Marketing Research; SAL 10:5-2, Call Reports/Reporting, for information on sales force feedback; MKT 50:7, Sources of Information, all subsections
      - 40:5-1 The Field of Marketing Intelligence
      - 40:5-2 Developing, Designing, Managing and Using Marketing Intelligence Systems, N.E.C.
      - 40:5-3 Competitive Intelligence
        - 40:5-3.1 Corporate Espionage
  - MKT 45. MARKETING IN AN ABNORMAL ECONOMY (Box 63)
    See also: ADV 0:3, Advertising in an Abnormal Economy; ADV 50:2, Continuity and Repetition in Advertising, all subsections; MKT 5:2-4, Demarketing Concept; MKT 55:6, Pricing Under Conditions of Economic Uncertainty; SAL 40:14, Selling in an Abnormal Economy
  - MKT 50. MARKETING RESEARCH
    - MKT 50:1 Role, General Theory and Elements of Marketing Research, N.E.C.
      See also: IOP 10:3-2, International Marketing Research, and subsections; MKT 40:4, Decision-Making in Marketing, and subsections; MKT 40:1-5, Marketing Research Management; ADM 0:2-10.30, Research in Public Relations; ADV 40, ADVERTISING RESEARCH, all subsections
      - 50:1-1 Marketing Research Costs (Box 64)
        See also: MKT 10, COSTS: MARKETING AND DISTRIBUTION, miscellaneous subsections
      - 50:1-2 Marketing Research Definitions and Terms
        See also: MKT 0:6, Marketing, Terms and Definitions; ADV 35:6, Media/Advertising Terms and Definitions
      - 50:1-3 ...(Year) Survey of Marketing Research (American Marketing Association)
    - MKT 50:2 Techniques of Marketing Research (only the most-often-used tools and techniques of marketing research are accorded individual subsections in the following breakdowns; includes strategies for communications research)
      - 50:2-1 Techniques of Marketing Research, in combination or N.E.C.
        See also: miscellaneous subsections for specific applications of individual research techniques; for example, MKT 50:2-4, Market Analysis and Sales Forecasting, which involves applications of such techniques as Scaling, Regression Analysis, Time Series Analysis, etc. See, in addition, the following individual research technique headings - starting with MKT 50:2-1.1. These headings are but a representative selection of techniques which crop up from time to time as part of questions relating to marketing research.
        - 50:2-1.1 Bayesian Approach
        - 50:2-1.2 Behavioral Analysis/Science, Attitude/Motivational Research, N.E.C.
        - 50:2-1.3 Binomial Distribution
          See also: Sampling
        - 50:2-1.4 Bivariate Analysis
        - 50:2-1.5 Canonical Analysis
        - 50:2-1.6 Causal Modeling
        - 50:2-1.7 Classical Statistical Analysis
        - 50:2-1.8 Cluster Analysis
        - 50:2-1.9 Cohort Analysis
        - 50:2-1.10 Conjoint Measurement
        - 50:2-1.11 Delphi Technique
        - 50:2-1.12 Discriminant Analysis
        - 50:2-1.13 Dynamic Programming
        - 50:2-1.14 Econometric Analysis
          See also ADM 0:2-4.5, Economic and Business Forecasting, N.E.C.
        - 50:2-1.15 Experimentation
        - 50:2-1.16 Factor Analysis
          See also: Latin Squares
        - 50:2-1.17 Feedback
        - 50:2-1.18 Fourier Analysis
        - 50:2-1.19 GERT (Graphic Evaluation and Review Technique) (Box 65)
        - 50:2-1.19 GERT (Graphic Evaluation and Review Technique) (Box 66)
        - 50:2-1.20 Group Discussion Technique
          See also: MKT 50:2-2.3, Group/Focus Group Interviewing
        - 50:2-1.21 Index Numbers
        - 50:2-1.22 Input/Output Analysis
        - 50:2-1.23 Latin Squares
        - 50:2-1.24 Linear and Non-Linear Programming
        - 50:2-1.25 Logical Flow Analysis
        - 50:2-1.26 Longitudinal Analysis
        - 50:2-1.27 Markov Processes
        - 50:2-1.28 Multidimensional Analysis
        - 50:2-1.29 Multivariate Analysis
        - 50:2-1.30 Probability Theory
        - 50:2-1.31 Projective Techniques
        - 50:2-1.32 Psychographics (Life-Style Measurement, including VALS)
        - 50:2-1.33 Queuing Theory
        - 50:2-1.34 Regression Analysis
        - 50:2-1.35 Sampling
        - 50:2-1.36 Scaling
        - 50:2-1.37 Sensitivity Analysis
        - 50:2-1.38 Sensorigraphics
        - 50:2-1.39 Sequential Analysis
        - 50:2-1.40 Shift Method
        - 50:2-1.41 Simulation
        - 50:2-1.42 Sociobiology
        - 50:2-1.43 Spectral/Cross-Spectral Analysis
        - 50:2-1.44 Technological Forecasting
        - 50:2-1.45 Time Series Analysis
        - 50:2-1.46 Variance/Covariance Analysis
        - 50:2-1.47 Verification/Validity/Reliability Procedures and Controls, N.E.C.
          See also: various subsections on Research; for example, MKT 50:2-2, Interviewers/Interviewing, N.E.C., and all subsections; MKT 50:2-3, Mail Surveys, N.E.C. and all subsections; MKT 50:2-4, Market Analysis and Sales Forecasting, N.E.C. and all subsections
        - 50:2-1.48 Voice Pitch Analysis (VOPAN); includes information on brain wave analysis
          See also: ADV 50:9-15, Visual and Other Autonomic Measurements
      - 50:2-2 Interviewers/Interviewing, N.E.C.
      - 50:2-2 Interviewers/Interviewing, N.E.C. (Box 67)
        See also: MKT 50:2-1.47, Verification/Validity/Reliability/Procedures and Controls, N.E.C.
        - 50:2-2.1 Linguistic Coding
        - 50:2-2.2 Elite and Opinion Leader Interviewing
        - 50:2-2.3 Group/Focus Group Interviewing
        - 50:2-2.4 Telephone Interviewing/Surveys; includes telephone interviewing in ad research
        - 50:2-2.5 Central Location Interviewing
      - 50:2-3 Mail Surveys, N.E.C.
        See also: ADV 45:5, Inquiry Stimulation Elements; ADV 35:3-8, Direct Mail, Incentives
        - 50:2-3.1 Response Rate Improvement
        - 50:2-3.2 Bias in Response
        - 50:2-3.3 Questionnaire Construction
          Includes how-to-do-it information on media audience measurement, recognition research, preference studies, readership studies, consumer panels. See also: ADV 50:5-5.10.3, Media-Sponsored Research: Preference Studies
      - 50:2-4 Market Analysis and Sales Forecasting, N.E.C.
      - 50:2-4 Market Analysis and Sales Forecasting, N.E.C. (Box 68)
        See also: specific research techniques in the MKT 50:2-1 subsections
        - 50:2-4.1 Marketing Objectives, Planning and Strategy, N.E.C.
          - 50:2-4.1.1 PIMS Project and Commentary (includes PIMS-Based studies relating to industrial ad expenditures and market share change) (Box 69)
          - 50:2-4.1.2 Sales & Marketing Management, Surveys of Buying Power
          - 50:2-4.1.3 Sales & Marketing Management, Surveys of Industrial and Commercial Buying Power
          - 50:2-4.1.4 Advertising Age Top Markets (discontinued)
          - 50:2-4.1.5 ADWEEK Hot Markets
        - 50:2-4.2 Market Segmentation, N.E.C.
          - 50:2-4.2.1 Marketing to Identified (e.g. segmented) Groups; i.e., minorities, youth, women, etc.
            See also: ADV 50:4-3.32, Women/Children/Models/Elderly in Copy/Commercials
            - 50:2-4.2.1.1 Identified or Segmented Groups in combination or N.E.C.
            - 50:2-4.2.1.2 Ethnic Market (Box 70)
              See also: ADV 50:4-3.23, Minorities/Ethnics in Copy/Commercials
            - 50:2-4.2.1.3 Women's Market
            - 50:2-4.2.1.4 Youth Market
        - 50:2-4.3 Market Share Measurement
          See also: MKT 50:2-4.1.1, PIMS Project & Commentary
        - 50:2-4.4 SIC Analysis and Research
          See also: ADV 50:5-4.14, Circulation: SIC Analysis
        - 50:2-4.5 ZIP Analysis and Research
    - MKT 50:3 Guidelines for Buying Research
    - MKT 50:4 Research Report Writing
      See also: ADM 0:2-7.2.7, Language Usage; ADM 0:2-7.2.13.1, Technical Writing; ADM 0:2-7.2.13, Writing; ADM 0:2-10.22, Media Publicity/Press Releases, N.E.C.; SAL 10:5-2, Call Reports/Reporting
    - MKT 50:5 Selling Management on the Value of Research/Information: Researcher/Management Relations
      See also: MKT 40:5, Marketing Intelligence and Information Systems; ADM 0:2-7.2.6, Information Systems and Retrieval
    - MKT 50:6 Ethics in Marketing Research; guidelines for "good" research; standards of practice